Telling you, Will, you got a real winner here.
我跟你说 Will 你这次真的买到宝了
She's just gonna love it.
她一定会非常喜欢的
Stacy, box her up.
Stacy 包上吧
Oh. Just the box.
放在盒子里就好
I'm sure it's prettier than the paper.
我想戒指肯定比包装纸好看吧
One tiny rock.
一颗小小的石头
So many other cool things I could have bought for myself.
有买这个的钱 我本可以给自己买多少好东西
Sam, Stacy, it's been a pleasure being ripped off by you.
Sam Stacy 很开心被你俩敲竹杠
Such a nice boy.
多好的一孩子
Too bad he's a handicap.
可惜是个残疾
Excuse me.
借过
Thank you.
谢谢
You all right, man? Take it easy, man!
你还好吗? 放松 哥们!
It's okay. It's okay.
没事的 没事的
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生 第八季第14集
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生 第八季第14集
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：ID 校对：ID 时间轴：玖玖
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：墨墨塔 小兰兰 校对：大叔我喜欢你老婆啊 时间轴：玖玖
Kid's a blind diabetic.
这孩子是个瞎子 还有糖尿病
He's hyperglycemic hyperosmolar.
我们原以为他是血糖过高
Which is what we thought until his blood tests showed a controlled sugar level and no ketones.
但验血结果显示血糖正常 而且没有甲酮
It could be caused by drug abuse. His tox screens were clean.
- 可能是毒品导致的 - 但毒性检测没有异常
You lying sack of crap.
你就满嘴跑火车吧
I have them right in front of me. Not you.
- 检查结果就在我面前 - 不是说你
This time. My former BFF.
这次 是我的前任好基友
He's S-M-I-T-B-A-W-A.
他S-M-I-T-B-A-W-A
Stabbing me in the back as we speak.
在我们讨论病情时在背后刺了老子一刀 (Stabbing me in the back as we speak)
Where exactly are you? If anyone should happen to ask,
- 你到底在哪儿呢啊? - 如果有人问起的话
I'm in an out-of-state medical conference until further notice.
除非我下达新命令 就说我去别的州参加医学会议了
Why would any- and... Don't really care.
- 为什么... - 没闲心关心你为什么这么做
Auditory hallucinations and disorientation could be signs of schizophrenia.
幻听和定向障碍是精神分裂症的症状
They did a psych consult. Mental status is normal.
他们对他进行了精神疾病的会诊 他精神状态完全正常
Seizure, noise-induced epilepsy- the sound of rush hour traffic could have set it off.
噪音引发的癫痫发作 可能是交通高峰时段的噪音导致其发病
Run an E.E.G. Blast his brain with harmonics to find out.
做个脑电图 用声音轰炸他的脑袋 好把病因找出来
Also, if anyone should further happen to ask,
还有 如果有人继续追问的话
I spent the whole last year in Africa with Doctors Without Boundaries.
我去年一整年都和无国界医生组织在非洲
Who are you hiding from?
你在躲谁啊?
Evil.
魔鬼
Where's House?
House哪儿去了?
Uh, he's at an out-of-state medical conference.
呃 他去别的州参加医学会议了
In Baltimore.
在巴尔的摩
I think.
我想是这样的
Nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你们
I'm Blythe, his mother.
我是Blythe 他的母亲
Do you want me to pick up the braille writer and laptop from your apartment?
你想让我去你公寓把盲人打字机 和笔记本电脑拿过来吗?
I don't plan on being here that long. I didn't eat lunch yesterday.
我在这待不了那么长时间的 我昨天没吃午餐
I probably just fainted. Or had an epileptic seizure.
- 我可能只是头晕而已 - 或者是癫痫发作
Which is only one possibility. I'm Doctor Chase.
这样就只有一种可能了 我是Chase医生
Uh, we'd like to discuss your case with you privately.
我们想和你单独谈谈你的病情
I'm his girlfriend. Is it all right if I stay for this? Melissa can stay.
- 我是他女朋友 我可以待在这吗? - Melissa可以留下来
And I've never had a seizure before in my life. They can be mild.
- 我这辈子还没经历过癫痫呢 - 癫痫可能不严重
Like a loss of concentration or a muscle tremor.
比如注意力涣散或者肌肉痉
A lot of times a family member notices before the patient does.
很多情况下家人会比病人更早注意到癫痫的发作
I'm Doctor Park, by the way.
我是Park医生 顺便说一句
I'm 5'2", Asian, and I'm totally cool with it
我身高5尺2寸 亚裔 如果你想摸摸我的脸
if you wanna feel my face. Blind people only do that in movies.
- 也完全没有问题 - 只有在电影里 盲人才会那么做
But you sound nice, so if you want me to...
但是你听上去很友善 所以如果你希望我...
Her point was, you may not have realized
她的意思是 你可能没有意识到
you were having a seizure, that maybe your girlfriend has?
癫痫的发作 但也许你女朋友注意到了?
No.
没有
But I-I haven't seen him for the last five months.
但我已经五个月没有见到他了
We were on a break. Like Rachel and Ross on Friends.
- 我们想分开来冷静一段时间 - 像老友记里的Rachel和Ross一样
Never seen the show myself, but I hear it's good.
虽然没看过那部剧 但用听的也知道拍得不错
That joke usually kills my blind friends.
这个笑话在我的盲人朋友里百听不厌
Will, this is serious. No, it's not.
- Will 这不是开玩笑的时候 - 不 没那么严重
Since I don't have epilepsy.
因为我没患癫痫
I have to pay attention to every signal my body sends or receives.
我得注意我身体发出和接收的每个信号
Or I end up taking a dirt nap.
否则我就长眠不醒了
You don't think I'd know if I was having seizures?
你以为我得了癫痫我自己会不知道吗?
It's probably just low blood sugar. If that's true, then you shouldn't have
- 可能只是低血糖而已 - 如果是那样的话 你就可以
a problem passing our test.
轻而易举地通过我们的检查了
How is he, James, really?
他怎么样了 James 说真的?
He's better than I've seen him in a long time. Is he happy?
- 他比之前很长一段时间都要好 - 他快乐吗?
It's okay.
没关系的
He's always been a complicated child.
他一直是个多愁善感的孩子
Were you in the hospital recently?
你最近住院了吗?
Oh, nothing serious. I just had a few moles removed yesterday
没什么 我不过是昨天去点了几个痣
and forgot I even had it on.
忘记把这摘掉了
Look, if Greg happens to get back early from the conference,
听着 如果Greg能早些回来的话
I'm staying at a hotel in town for the next three days.
我接下来的三天都会待在宾馆里
I would like him to call me. I will pass it on.
- 我希望他能给我打个电话 - 我会转告他的
Thank you.
谢谢你
Um, do you think that they would mind if I got a refill for the road?
你说我去续杯 带着路上喝 他们会介意吗?
Not at all. Good.
- 不会的 - 那就好
Not seeing any seizure activity in response to low frequency sounds.
在低频声音刺激下 没有出现癫痫
I'm starting him on mid-range. Have you seen his girlfriend?
- 开始进行中频刺激 - 你见过他女朋友没?
Extremely hot.
非常漂亮
Blind people can't have attractive girlfriends? Not my point.
- 盲人就不能有漂亮的女朋友了? - 我不是这个意思
He actually convinced her to go for the whole relationship break thing.
事实上是他说服她两人需要分开的
How do you know it wasn't her idea? Because she's back with him.
- 你怎么知道这不是她的主意? - 因为她回到他身边了
Women suggest a break when they wanna break up.
女人们提出分开 是因为她们想分手
Men do it because they wanna have sex with other women before they settle down.
男人们这么做是因为他们想在结婚前和别的女人做爱
They're a little young to get married, don't you think?
他们现在结婚有点太早了 你不这么觉得吗?
I was their age when I did.
我像他们这么大时 早就结婚了
I see your point.
我明白你的意思了
HE'S SEIZING
他癫痫发作了
Sound frequency's at 300 hertz.
声音频率是300赫兹
It's not a seizure.
这不是癫痫
He's not spiking on his E.E.G.
他的脑电图上没有出现峰值
He's not moving air.
他出不来气了
I I think he's choking on something.
我想他被什么东西卡住了
Blood. I don't see any blockage.
有血 我没看到任何物体
Help me move him.
帮我把他抬起来
Just relax and breathe.
放轻松 深呼吸
What-what are these?
这些是什么东西?
Three teeth detached from his jawbone and lodged in his throat.
三颗牙从他的下颌骨脱落 卡在了他的喉咙里
He almost choked to death on them. Environmental?
- 他差点被噎死 - 环境引发的吗?
Could be heavy metal poisoning or radiation exposure.
可能是重金属中毒或是辐射
Then he wouldn't be the only one.
那发病的不可能只有他一个人
He's an accountant who works on the same floor with 50 other people.
他是个会计 和另外50个人在同一层楼工作
Maybe his girlfriend poisoned him.
可能是他女朋友给他下的毒
House usually thinks that's a good guess.
House通常会觉得这是种不错的猜想
And she's gotta be pissed off and have low self-esteem.
而且她受了刺激 自尊心又不强
Why else would she give him a free pass to pork other women?
要不她怎么会同意让他去跟别的女人乱搞呢?
Because he's handicapped. Women feel sorry for us.
因为他是个残疾 女人们同情我们
This cane is tail bait. Where are you now?
- 我手里的拐杖就是钓美眉的鱼饵 - 你现在在哪?
Expect an actual answer this time?
你以为他会跟你说实话吗?
Hi, guys. Was wondering if House's mother left yet.
嗨 同志们 我想知道House的老妈走了没
He won't let me go to a hos- It's not environmental, it's periodontitis.
- 他不让我去医... - 不是环境引发的 是牙周炎
An oral infection doesn't explain his disorientation and auditory hallucinations.
口腔感染不能解释他的定向障碍和幻听
They're laughing because they know diabetes exacerbates the condition.
他们嘲笑你是因为他们知道糖尿病会加重病情
It could progress to a systemic disease.
这可能会发展成为全身性疾病
The bacteria spread and affect other organs. Like his brain.
病毒扩散 感染了其他器官 比如他的大脑
Start him on broad spectrum antibiotics and book him an appointment with a periodontist.
给他用广谱抗生素 再给他预约个牙周病医生
He has fake children now, too?
他现在连假孩子都有了?
You think I'm not good enough for your mother.
你觉得你老妈看不上我
Not in front of the kids, Honey.
别在孩子们面前这么说嘛 亲爱的
Hey, add a couple of flies, toss in a dead goat or two, we might have a winner.
嘿 加几只苍蝇 再来一两头死山羊 没准你就获胜了呢
She gone?
她走了?
Yeah.
是的
We really need to talk.
我们得谈谈
Okay. Crayons down.
好了 放下蜡笔吧
Line up if you wanna get paid.
如果你想要钱的话 就排好队
It's the only time I ever successfully lie to my mom;
这是唯一一次我对我老妈编瞎话成功
is through the elaborate preparations and props.
通过了精心的准备和布置
I said no Transformers, Slick.
我说过不许画变形金刚 小滑头
Stay here until the coast is clear.
待在这 等到警报解除再走
Fine.
好的
But you sleep on couch tonight. You sleeping with her now?
- 但今晚你去睡沙发 - 你现在跟她一起睡了?
Just in case an I.N.S. guy comes in through the window.
以防移民归化局从窗户偷窥我们
Yeah, she didn't buy it either. You need to talk to your mother.
- 没错 她也不吃我这套 - 你得跟你妈妈谈谈
When I'm ready.
等我准备好了再说
Still need to get a fake passport, doctored photos, maybe a case of Aids.
还得弄个假护照 PS过的照片 要不编个艾滋病的故事
She's sick, House.
她病了 House
Did she say that? She was wearing a hospital admission bracelet
- 她亲口告诉你的? - 她戴着医院的住院手镯
and carrying around a book on dealing with terminal cancer.
还带着一本如何应对晚期癌症的书
I'm sorry.
我很遗憾
She's staying at the Grand for the next three days.
她接下来的三天都待在酒店里
The antibiotics will stop the infection from spreading further.
抗生素会阻止感染进一步扩散
And I'll spare you the lecture you'll get from the periodontist tomorrow,
鉴于你明天就要去看牙医了 我今天就不说你什么了
but you need to practice better oral hygiene.
但你得保持良好的口腔卫生
So are you guys saying this is happening because, what,
所以你们是说我这样是因为
- I didn't floss enough? - Probably didn't help,
- 我没剔干净牙齿? - 可能不是因为这个原因
but diabetics are prone to this type of infection.
但是糖尿病人容易患这种感染
Half the time, he doesn't even bother getting undressed before he goes to bed.
一半的时间里 他睡觉前连衣服都懒得脱
Can only imagine how many times you've skipped brushing your teeth since we-
我可以想象你有多少次没刷牙 自从我们...
sorry. I don't mean to lecture you, babe.
抱歉 我不是要数落你什么的 宝贝
Well, I guess you're right.
我想你说得对
Look, you haven't eaten anything all day.
听着 你一天都没吃东西了
Why don't you go grab a bite? I'll be fine.
你去吃点东西吧? 我这里没事
All right, well, I'll see you in an hour, okay? Not if I see you first.
- 好的 那一小时后见吧? - 除非我能先看见你
I was wondering if I could ask you guys for a favor.
我在想我能不能求你们帮我一个忙
I really need my laptop and braille writer, and I can't ask Melissa to get them for me.
我非常需要我的笔记本和盲人打字机 但我不能让Melissa帮我去拿
Why not? Because...
- 为什么? - 因为...
I want you to put this someplace safe.
我想让你们把这放在一个安全的地方
It's beautiful.
真漂亮
People always say diamonds are beautiful.
人们总是说钻石好看
But to me they just feel cold. They have really sharp edges.
但对我来说不过是冷冰冰的石头 而且棱角非常锋利
I guess convincing her to take a break was a good thing.
我想说服她分开一段时间是件好事
Well, the break was her idea. Melissa's the only girl I've ever dated.
分开是她的主意 我只跟Melissa一个人谈过恋爱
She wanted me to be sure before we... took the next step.
她想让我确定好自己的心意 在我们发展到下一步之前
Yeah.
是啊
What are you doing? We're here.
- 你在干什么? - 我们既然都来了
We might as well search the place in case we're wrong about periodontitis.
不妨再检查一下这个地方 以防我们弄错了牙周病的事情
What are you doing? We're here. Might as well eat.
- 你在干什么? - 我们既然都来了 不妨大吃一顿
You're stealing food from a blind man?
你从一个盲人家里偷东西吃?
We're doing him a favor. He owes me.
我们在帮他的忙诶 他欠我的
I take it from your low self-esteem theory
我想你说那套自尊心不强的理论
you have some experience with relationship breaks?
是因为你有过类似经历吧?
What happened?
怎么回事?
He talked me in it, then...
他劝我分开冷静一段时间 然后...
Slept with three of my friends. Then dumped my ass.
他跟我的三个朋友上了床 然后把我给甩了
College boyfriend. Thought he was the love of my life.
大学时的男友 还以为他是我的真命天子呢
Then why agree to a break?
那你为什么还同意分开?
My self-esteem wasn't as high back then.
我的自尊心那时候还没那么强
No one's is.
大家都不强
Sugar free!
无糖的!
Ugh. Disgusting.
啊 太恶心了
I'll check the bathroom. You keep checking the snacks,
我去浴室检查一下 你继续检查零食
Greg. Sorry I didn't call first.
- Greg - 抱歉我没有事先打电话来
I just flew back from my conference.
我刚开完会回来
Um, this-this really isn't, uh-
这... 这真的不是...
I need your medical records
我需要你的医疗记录
and the name of your primary physician.
还有你主治医生的名字
Well, you remember Mr. Bell.
你还记得Bell先生吧
Well, if I didn't, I will now.
就算我以前不记得 现在肯定是忘不了
You're not dying?
你不是要死了?
I, uh... I may have mislead James
我... 我可能误导了James
by letting him see a book on cancer.
通过让他看到一本关于癌症的书
We did, however, have some expectations that you might call first.
然而 我们以为你会先打电话过来的
Yeah.
是啊
This isn't how I envisioned you finding out.
我没想到你会以这种方式发现
Mr. Bell and I, we're...
Bell先生和我 我们...
Having sex, got it. Getting married.
- 滚床单了 我明白 - 要结婚了
Also.
同时
We wanted you to be the first to know.
我想让你成为第一个知道的人
I need 10 milligrams of benzodiazepine.
给我10毫升苯二氮
Help me hold him down.
帮我压住他
I'm putting epilepsy back on the table. And I'm taking it off because it doesn't explain losing his teeth.
- 我要把癫痫重新纳入考虑范围 - 我要把它去掉因为这解释不了牙齿脱落
The kid's diabetic. The periodontitis could be real but completely unrelated.
这孩子有糖尿病 牙周炎可能确有其事 但可能与他的病完全不相关
Coincidence. Buying that, House?
巧合啊 你相信吗 House?
Until I hear something that takes my mind off
除非我听到让我能从今天下午一老头的"侏罗鸡"
the Jurassic schlong that I was traumatized by this afternoon.
给我造成的创伤中走出来的想法
I know what's wrong with the patient.
我知道病人怎么了
Illegal drugs. Some kind of acid.
非法药品 某种致幻剂
His tox screens were clean. His apartment wasn't.
- 他的毒品检查显示他没吸毒啊 - 但他的公寓不是
We didn't find any drugs.
我们什么毒品都没找到啊
Then why am I completely tripping balls right now?
那我现在怎么感觉脑袋不是我自己的呢?
I'm seriously freaking out here, guys.
我真的很恐慌 同志们
Can't you tell?
你们难道没看出来吗?
You pretty much look the same as you always do.
你跟平常看起来差不多
Take your glasses off.
把你眼镜摘了
Pupils dilated...
瞳孔放大...
Pulse elevated. Hallucinating?
心率加快 出现幻觉了吗?
I think so, because...
我想是的 因为...
He's a rabbit.
他是只兔子
Oh, I get it.
我明白了
Because she's his wife.
因为她是他的老婆
They flirt a lot. I've seen things.
他们经常调情 我都看到了
Mm, Taub- Taub is either...
嗯 Taub... Taub要么是...
A tooth fairy or... Rainbow Brite.
牙仙子 要么是... 彩虹仙子
And you...
而你...
You're just House.
你还是House
She ate ice cream and Gummi Bears at the patient's apartment.
她在病人家吃了冰淇淋和软糖
One of 'em must have been dosed with it.
其中一样一定掺了药
Go back and find the drugs. You two, find out where he bought them,
回去把毒品找出来 你们俩 查出他是从哪里买到的
and then MRI his brain. Check for infections, masses, and plaques.
然后给他大脑做个MRI 检查一下感染 肿块和血小板
Am I gonna die?
我会死吗?
We'll get back to you on that.
我们一会再来告诉你
I've been blind since birth.
我一生下来就看不见
I thought maybe if I tried LSD,
我以为如果我试下迷幻药
I might, you know... Colors... a shape.
我可能 你知道 会看到颜色啊 形状啊
I just- I just wanted to see something.
我只是想看到些什么
How many times? Maybe five or six.
- 你用过多少次? - 也许五次 也许六次
We need to know where you bought it so we can find out what was in it.
我们得知道你是从哪买的 这样我们好知道成分是什么
My girlfriend gave it to me.
是我女朋友给我的
I'll find her. No, don't.
- 我去找她 - 不 不要
It-it wasn't Melissa. I met someone else.
不是Melissa 我遇到了别的女孩
When were you planning on telling her that,
你打算什么时候告诉她这件事
before or after you ask her to marry you?
在你求婚前还是求婚后?
The ring isn't for her. We were on a break.
戒指不是给她的 我们分开了
She wanted me to see what else was out there, and I did.
她想让我看看外面的世界 而我这么做了
I was gonna tell her the other night, but I ended up here instead.
我那晚本想告诉她的 但结果我进了医院
We just need to talk to the one who supplied the drugs.
我们只需要和提供药品的人谈谈
She's on vacation with her parents.
她和她父母度假去了
This is her cell. I don't want her to know I'm in the hospital.
这是她的电话号码 我不想让她知道我在医院
She'll only freak out. That's very considerate of you.
- 她会吓坏了的 - 你还真是体贴啊
You think this is easy for me.
你觉得这对我来说很容易
I know I have to tell Melissa.
我知道我得告诉Melissa
Well, what's stopping you? She's still one of my best friends.
- 那你为什么不这么做? - 她还是我最好的朋友之一
And I don't want to be alone in here.
我不想一个人待在这
Have you seen your mother yet? She's not dying.
- 你去见你母亲了吗? - 她没有要死
She was having sex with my father.
她在跟我父亲上床
Ignore her. She's on acid.
别理她 她吃迷幻药了
Your father's dead, House.
你父亲已经去世了 House
Not the dead dad, the biological dad.
不是死掉的那个 是我的亲生老爹
The one I pointed out to you at fake father's funeral.
我在冒牌父亲的葬礼上指给你的那个
Are you sure?
你确定吗?
Your only evidence is that birthmark you saw when you were 12.
你唯一的证据是你12岁的时候看到的那块胎记
Well, now I've seen two.
现在我看到两块了
Good news is I won't technically be a bastard much longer.
好消息是我很快就不是私生子了
We're gonna be one big crappy family.
我们会成为讨厌一家人
Well, that's- that's great news.
那是... 那是个好消息
Your mother won't be alone anymore, and you can finally get to know the guy.
你母亲不会那么孤单了 你也终于可以了解这个人了
Yes, that is one option.
是的 我可以那样做
Are you saying you're not even curious?
你是说你对他一点都不好奇吗?
You want to know what I think? I think you know the answer to that question.
你知道我是怎么想的吗? 我想你知道那个问题的答案
You avoid your mother because she's the one person whose opinion you actually care about.
你不想见你母亲是因为 你只在乎她的想法
If that was true, you'd have every reason to shut up. I avoid my mother because she's boring.
如果那是真的 那你丫还不赶紧闭嘴 我不见我母亲是因为她很无趣
That's why you've been so open and honest about prison and marrying a complete stranger.
所以你在蹲过监狱和娶一个陌生人的问题上如此开放和诚实
Even if I care what she thinks, why would I care what some sperm donor does?
就算我在乎她的想法 可我为毛要在乎一个精子捐助者的想法呢?
You read the guy's book about three times. Years ago.
- 你把那个人写的书读了三遍 - 那时多少年前的事了
It took three times because it was so badly written.
我读了三遍是因为他写得太差了
Oh, I get it.
我知道了
The second birthmark was on his penis, right?
第二块胎记在他的小鸡鸡上 对吧?
He's a dick. You've been working for House for months
- 他是个混蛋 - 你给House干了好几个月的活了
and just now realized that disabled people can also be dicks?
才意识到残疾人也会是混蛋?
What he's doing now to that girl isn't fair. The break was her idea.
- 他对那个女孩的所作所为是不公平的 - 分开是她的主意
And now she thinks they're back together.
可现在她想让两人重新在一起了
He's a scared, sick, blind kid who doesn't want to be alone.
他是个恐惧 生病 又失明的孩子 他不想一个人
You really don't get that?
你真的不理解吗?
I do, but...
我理解 但是...
What is it?
怎么了?
Not good news for him... Or Park.
对他来说不是个好消息... Park也是
Where's Park? Wilson's babysitting her.
- Park呢? - Wilson在照顾她
Talking about the fact that she could have
正说着她可能遭受
permanent brain damage might bum her trip out a little bit.
永久性脑损伤的事实 以致危及到她的前途的问题
A dark spot doesn't necessarily equal brain damage.
一个黑点不足以说明是脑损伤
It could be a congenital malformation
可能是先天畸形
connected with his blindness or a tumor.
和他失明有关 或者是肿瘤
A clot. Exactly.
- 是血栓 - 没错
We need to do another scan, but inject dye and figure out-
我们可以再做一个扫描 但是注入染料 然后看看...
I said "a clot," not "or a clot. "
我说"是血栓" 不是 "可能是血栓 "
It's a clot.
这就是血栓
Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis. Good news for Park.
- 脑静脉窦血栓形成 - 对Park来说 是好消息
I've never seen one present this large before.
我还从没见过这么大的
It fits. When it was smaller,
这样吻合 血栓小的时候
it caused his initial disorientation and hallucinations.
导致了他之前方向障碍 以及幻觉的出现
As it grew larger, the seizures.
肿瘤变大 就导致心脏病发作
If left untreated, it leads to cerebral edema and death.
如果不治疗的话 就会导致脑水肿和死亡
But what causes that and tooth loss?
可是什么导致掉牙齿的呢
Any hyper-coagulable state. Lupus?
任何高凝状态都会 红斑狼疮?
I counter your lupus with Behcet's syndrome.
我用白塞病对抗你的狼疮
No, he doesn't have any of the earlier symptoms-
不对 他没有任何的早期症状
color blindness, abnormal visual fields or-
色盲 视野缺损 或是...
we've been ignoring his eyes because he's blind.
我们始终忽略了他的眼睛 因为他是盲人
Well, if he wasn't before, he would be by now.
如果他以前不是 现在也是
Confirm with an eye exam, start treatment with heparin for the clot.
去做眼部检查求证 用肝素治疗血块
Interferon and steroids for the Behcet's.
用干扰素和类固醇治疗白塞病
No, no!
不 别啊
Give me back my teeth! Park, listen. Park-
- 把我的牙齿还给我 - Park 听我说 Park
You're a tooth thief! No, no, no. Stop it, stop it!
- 你这个偷牙鬼 - 不 不 别丢了 住手
Ki-ki-ki! Back on the couch.
坐回沙发上去
What are you doing to this poor girl?
你把这个小丫头怎么了啊
It's not what it looks like. She-oh!
不是看起来这样的 她....
She's tripping on acid.
她是嗑药发颠了
Good lord, man, that's no way to treat a bad trip.
天啊 怎么可以这样对待嗑错药的人
Put the chair down. You'll end up hurting the poor wee thing.
把椅子放下 你会伤害这个小不点的
There you are.
这样才对
Hello, darlin'.
你好啊 亲爱的
I'm Thomas, and this beautiful creature here is Blythe.
我是Thomas 这美丽的造物是Blythe
Is there anything we can do to help you? That rabbit stole my teeth.
- 有什么可以帮忙的吗 - 那鸟人偷了我的牙齿
Of course he did, but I'll tell you what he's done.
当然了 不过我告诉你他还干了什么
He's put them back again, and they're twice as nice as they used to be.
他把牙齿还给你了 比以前还要漂亮整洁哟
You can feel them if you like.
你要是愿意 可以感受一下
See?
瞧见没
Now, why don't we sit on this nice comfy couch,
不如我们坐在这张舒服的沙发上
have a nice cool drink and talk all about it.
喝一杯 好好聊一下
Would you like that?
你愿意吗
He's had some experience with things like this,
他处理这种事情很有经验的
back in the day. As I recall, both of us-
- 在过去 - 我印象中 我们两个都是
Uh, not the time or the place, dear.
现在不是时候 地方也不对 亲爱的
There you are.
这就对了
See? There you are.
瞧 没事了
There's no way that guy's related to you.
这老头儿绝对不是你亲生的
There's fresh scarring and swelling in both fundi,
两边大脑基底都有新的伤疤和肿大
and a bleed on the left. House was right.
左边有出血 House是对的
It's Behcet's syndrome.
是白塞病
Give it to me straight, Doc.
说直白点吧 医生
Am I ever gonna see again?
我还能再看到吗
That's a little out of our jurisdiction.
这不是我们能负责的
We need to wrap a dressing over your eyes to keep the light out.
我们需要盖住你的眼睛 不接触光线的照射
Not really a problem for me.
对我来说不是什么问题
You might not see it, but your tissue does. It'll also help with the swelling.
你也许看不到 但脑部组织可以 这对肿大也有帮助
I'll leave you in Dr. Adams' capable hands.
我就把你交给Adams医生万能的双手了
You think I'm an ass, don't you?
你觉得我是个混蛋 不是吗
I can tell by your breathing.
从你的呼吸声中 我能感受出来
Either you're angry or fat.
要么你是生气 要么就是你太胖了
I think it's unfair that you're leading on a woman
我觉得你不该这样骗一个爱你 在乎你的女人
I love and care about her too.
我也爱她 在乎她的
But we just don't work together as a couple.
但我们不适合在一起
You need to tell her that. I'm going to.
- 你应该亲口告诉她 - 我想说的
But I just want to do it the right way.
但我不想随随便便地一说
I don't want her to hate me.
我不想她恨我
When she finds out you bought an engagement ring for another woman, that option is out the window.
等她发现你给其他女人买订婚戒指 你还能有什么选择
It was gonna be for her.
本来是想送给她的
What changed?
是什么让你改变了心意
She told me we were going on a break.
她说我们要分手
I didn't even get a say in the matter.
我连发表意见的权利都没有
She wanted you to be sure about your relationship.
她希望你能确定自己的感情
I can see how that would be annoying.
我能明白那有多讨厌
I think I liked it better when you were just breathing angrily.
我想你还是满怀愤怒地喘粗气好了
She still sees me as the same sheltered, blind geek she met in college.
她依然把我看作是那个 在大学里认识的瞎子宅男
Most of the time she acts more like my mother than my girlfriend.
有时她更像是我妈 而不是女朋友
I asked her to marry me.
我有向她求婚
She tells me I need to date somebody else first.
她却说我应该先和别人约会试试
I'd rather she just dumped me. At least that I can understand.
我宁愿她甩了我 至少那样我就能理解
So you were hurt so much you had to marry the next woman you met?
于是你很受伤 决定和下一个认识的女人结婚?
Julie doesn't see me as I was, but for who I am now.
Julie眼中的我 不是过去那个 而是现在的我
She trusts me to make my own decisions and to help her with hers.
她相信我作出的决定 也让我帮助她拿主意
For the first time in my life, I have somebody who needs me...
这辈子第一次 有人需要我
Instead of the other way around.
而不是其他的
Ah, she finally fell asleep. I think she'll be fine in a couple of hours.
她终于睡着了 过几个小时应该就没事了
How do you know about handling a bad acid trip?
你怎么会处理吃错药的情况?
Friends in your gardening club been experimenting again?
你园艺俱乐部的朋友又在试验了?
I was young once.
我也曾年轻过
A little scrapbook that Thomas threw together.
Thomas的剪贴簿
He even has a couple of pictures of you as a child.
还有几张你小时候的照片呢
And I've known Greg almost since he was born, you know.
我差不多从Greg出生时就认识他了
His father and I were like brothers. I was a Navy chaplain in those days.
他父亲和我就像兄弟 那时我是海军的随军牧师
I left the service in the late '60s.
我是60年代末退役的
I don't think his dad ever forgave me for protesting the war.
我想他爸爸一直都无法原谅我反对战役的做法
Of course, if he knew I'd got Blythe involved...
当然 他要是知道我让Blythe也参与进来
You protested the war? When?
你反对战争 什么时候的事?
You were a child. I didn't share my entire schedule with you.
你那时还小 我不能事事都跟你报备吧
We knew if we told you, you'd tell him, and he'd kill us both.
我们知道要是告诉你 你就会告诉他 他会把我俩都杀了的
He was a marine. It was the ultimate betrayal.
他是海军 那可是最大逆不道
Penultimate.
排倒数第二
Sweetheart, I think we need to get back to the hotel.
亲爱的 我们应该回酒店去了
Wilson, it's been a real pleasure.
Wilson 见到你很高兴
You're right. Much too formal.
是啊 太正式了
Come here, lad.
过来 伙计
We're practically family now.
我们现在是一家人了
We'll see you boys tonight.
我们今晚见
8:00 sharp.
8点整
I invited them out to dinner. Told them it was your idea.
我邀请他们吃晚餐 说是你的主意
Straw.
吸管
I know we agreed that whatever happened on break
我知道咱们说好 分开阶段发生的事
would stay on break, and I don't expect you to talk about yours.
不会影响以后 我也不指望你说出自己发生过什么
But I just want you to know that there was no one else.
但我想你知道 这里没有别人
I missed you so much,
我很想你
I barely even saw my own friends.
我都没怎么见我的朋友
I'm just so glad it's finally over. Are you okay?
我很高兴一切终于结束了 你还好吗
What's happening to him?
他怎么了
Is he going to be okay? I'm going to need to discuss that with my colleagues.
- 他不会有事吧 - 我要和我的同事们商量一下
We have to talk.
我们得谈谈
No, you need to rest. I have to tell you about...
- 不 你需要休息 - 我要跟你说...
About what happened on break.
分开这些日子发生的事
Later. You just lie back and relax- stop it, Melissa!
- 改天再说 你躺好休息吧 - 不 Melissa!
Just stop telling me what I need,
别再说我需要什么
and listen for once, okay?
就听我说一次 好吗
How are you feeling? Embarrassed.
- 你感觉如何 - 很丢脸
I'm still not sure what was real
我依然不确定什么是真实
or what I hallucinated.
什么是我的幻想
Did you try to kiss me?
你是有吻我吗
What about you?
那你呢
He's stabilized for the moment.
他眼下情况正稳定
Coughing up blood. That doesn't really change anything.
咳血 这并不能改变什么
Hemoptysis is a symptom of Behcet's.
咳血是白塞病的症状之一
Except our treatment should make him better, not worse. It could be doing both.
- 但是我们的治疗应该让他有所好转 不是恶化 - 两种都有可能的
Our treatment breaks down his clot in his head,
我们的治疗让他脑部的血栓散掉
like it's supposed to, except a piece broke off
本该如此 ...除非有血块掉落
and traveled to one of his arteries in his lungs.
进入了他肺部的动脉中
If anything, we need to increase the heparin to prevent further clots from forming.
我们应该增加肝素来预防更多的血栓形成
If we do that and he starts hemorrhaging, we won't be able to stop the bleeding.
如果这样做导致出血 我们很难止血的
If we don't do that, the next clot could cause a heart attack or a stroke.
如果不这么做 就会有另一个血栓 引起心脏病或是中风
Park's way, he at least has a shot at living.
依照Park的办法 他还有活的机会
CT his lungs to confirm, and up the dose.
给他肺部做CT确认 增加剂量
She's young and hot. She'll bounce back.
她年轻又漂亮 会复原的
82 pounds.
82磅
How much weight I put on when my break ended the same way.
我分手时就胖了这么多
People were calling me Park-ing-lot.
人们叫我 停车场
Hmm... Almost 9:00.
嗯...快9:00了
I think your boy is gonna stand us up. No, no, he'll be here.
- 估计你儿子要放我们鸽子了 - 不 不 他会到的
Practically walked in on us having sex.
在我们做爱时撞进来
God, if I saw my mother doing that, I'd claw my own eyes out.
天啊 如果我看到我妈这样 我会自戳双眼的
Of course, she was nowhere near as attractive as you.
当然了 她可没你迷人
Horribly fat, as a matter of fact.
事实上 过胖
Mother...
老妈...
Guy sleeping with my mother,
睡我妈的先生
this is Dominika, my wife.
这是Dominika 我的妻子
It's so nice to be meeting you.
很高兴见到你们
Gregory tells me that you were born in Richmond, Virginia,
Gregory告诉我你是在弗吉尼亚州 里士满出生的
and your father was a tailor who stole from his clients.
你父亲是个喜欢顺手牵羊的裁缝
James has persuaded me of the value
James让我理解了交往中
of openness and honesty in relationships.
开放与诚实的价值
We see people with disabilities all the time, but...
我们总看到有残疾的人 但...
Seeing and understanding aren't always the same thing.
看到和理解 不总是一样的
Are you talking to me or writing a Facebook post?
你在和我说话 还是在写脸书?
I'm saying we should have picked up on the degeneration in his eyes sooner.
我是说 我们应该更早发现他眼睛的退化
We ignored them because we assumed they weren't even part of the equation.
我们无视了 因为我们想当然地以为 那不是其中一个因素
I also realized, intellectually,
我同样认识到 智力上
I may understand what it means to be disabled, but emotionally, I didn't have a clue.
我也许理解残疾的意义 但感情上 我毫无头绪
Apparently, his girlfriend didn't either.
显然他女朋友也没有
So you're back on his side? It's not a side. It's a perspective.
- 所以你又站在他那边了? - 不是挑站哪边 而是观点问题
He just wants to be treated like an adult, make his own decisions.
他只想被看作成年人 自己做决定
I may not agree with all of them, but how the hell can I judge him?
我也许没法完全同意 但我怎么能对他品头论足呢?
I'm sure that's exactly what disabled people want, to be treated like completely foreign entities,
我相信这就是残疾人想听到的 完全被当作异类看待
incapable of being judged and understood.
无法被批判和理解
Park was right about the clot.
Park说的血栓没错
Hopefully the anticoagulants keep it from killing him.
希望抗凝血剂能阻止它要他的命
So... She gets the couch on the odd nights, and I get the bed on evens.
那么...奇数日她睡沙发 偶数日我睡床
In exchange for a federal felony,
为了不获联邦重罪
she gets a green card, and I get a live-in maid.
她拿到绿卡 我多了个住家佣人
Good for you.
你厉害
The immigration policy in this country is a travesty.
这个国家的移民政策太滑稽了
It forces people to lie just so nice people can stay here.
逼迫人们说谎 才能好好留下来
Thank you... Dad.
谢谢...爸爸
I'm grateful you approve.
我很感激得到你的赞同
You should also know that I was not in Africa the last year.
你还应该知道去年我没在非洲
You were in jail.
你在监狱里
I've been reading the Princeton police blotter
从你搬到这后 我一直在看普林斯顿警察记事簿
And I'm afraid I haven't been truthful with you either.
恐怕我也没有一直对你诚实
And I've wanted to tell you this for a very long time.
我很久之前就想告诉你了
Thomas and I...
Thomas和我...
We got married two months after your father passed away.
在你父亲去世两个月后结婚
Uh-huh. You understand, we didn't want you to think we were disrespecting
- 啊哈 - 你要明白 我们不想让你以为
the memory of your father.
我们在玷污你父亲的名声
And... Is there another secret that you want to share with me?
然后...还有秘密还要和分享吗?
No.
没有了
There's nothing you think might be relevant
不觉得可能有什么
to my life?
与我的生活有关?
Like... What? I don't know.
- 比如...什么? - 我不知道
Just off the top of my head,
突然想起来
something like I DNA-tested my dad and found that
我DNA测试了我爸 发现
he was not my biological father- you are.
他不是我的生身父亲 你才是
That's impossible.
不可能
People lie. Birthmarks don't.
人会撒谎 胎记不会
Oh, my God!
我的天啊!
You told me he was a premie.
你告诉我他是个早产儿
This bloody lunatic is my son!
这该死的疯子是我儿子!
He's not a lunatic.
他不是疯子
All those years you could have told me. I could have done things.
那些年你本可以告诉我 我能做出些改变
That could have made a difference in the boy's life.
可能会在这孩子的人生中做出些改变
I think we should all just calm down. Look at him sitting there-
- 我们都冷静一下吧... - 看他坐在那
a pill-popping sociopath!
一个嗑药的反社会份子!
If you wanted to screw up his life, you couldn't have done it better.
如果你想毁了他的人生 那你做到了极致
He's got you there, mom.
他说对了 妈
He's one of the most well-respected doctors in the world.
他是世界上最受尊重的医生之一
He's saved more lives than you can count.
他救活的人你都数不过来
Now, you apologize to him, or I swear,
现在向他道歉 不然我发誓
you will never see me again, Thomas.
你再也见不到我了 Thomas
I can't deal with this anymore.
我受不了了
He's my son?
他是我儿子?
I'm having a bloody breath of fresh air,
我去呼吸一口新鲜空气
that's what I'm doing.
我走了
So, who's for dessert?
那么 谁要甜点?
Somebody help me!
谁来救救我!
Uhh! Somebody-
啊! 有没有人...
Will? It's Dr. Adams and Dr. Chase.
Will? 是Adams医生和Chase医生
We just need to know- My eyes! My eyes!
- 我们只需要知道... - 我的眼睛! 我的眼睛!
It feels like it's on fire!
火烧火燎的
It's not behcet's.
不是白塞病
It doesn't necrotize tissue like this.
不会像这样使组织坏死
I think it's streptococcus pyogenes.
我认为是化脓链球菌
Except we've already treated him with broad spectrum antibiotics.
只不过我们已经用广谱抗生素治疗他
It shouldn't be spreading. It should be dying. Just means it's drug-resistant.
- 不应该扩散 应该消亡的 - 意味着这是抗药性
We need to remove what's left of his eyes before the gangrene sets in.
我们要在产生坏疽前把他眼睛里的东西清掉
It's something that looks and acts like a bacteria but isn't one.
看起来 活动起来像细菌 但不是
Could be viral. No, it couldn't.
- 可能是病毒 - 不 不可能
There's no evidence of viral markers in the necrotized tissue.
坏死组织上没有病毒标记的证据
Let me see that image you took last night of the clot in his lung.
让我看看你昨晚给他拍的肺部血栓照片
That's not a piece of the clot from his brain.
不是他脑部的血栓
That's the point of infection.
是感染点
Mucormycosis.
毛霉菌病
He breathed in the spores, it's been growing and spreading ever since.
他在孢子中呼吸 从那开始生长传播
A fungal infection spreading this fast? Kid's a diabetic.
- 真菌感染传播这么快? - 那孩子有糖尿病
He already has a compromised immune system.
他的免疫系统已经不完善
He's right. This sample from his eyes is crawling with it.
没错 取自他眼睛的样本里满是霉菌
Treat with amphotericin b.
用二性霉素B治疗他
We treated him with gentamicin when we thought it was bacterial,
我们以为是细菌时用庆大霉素治疗他
which means the dose of amphotericin b we'll need
也就是为了治愈他 我们需要的
to cure him will probably leave him deaf.
二性霉素B的剂量 可能会导致他失聪
Sorry, I stopped listening after you said
抱歉 你说"我们需要治愈他的剂量"时
"the dose we'll need to cure him. "
我就没听了
Blind and deaf?
失明还是失聪?
I'd rather be dead.
我宁愿死
You will be.
你会死的
I can live with that.
我可以接受
You never did get my humor.
你从来不懂我的幽默
There's a chance your hearing won't be completely gone.
你的听力有可能不会完全丧失
How much of a chance?
多大机会?
A small one.
机会很小
But a chance.
但也是个机会
I'm-I'm refusing treatment.
我...我拒绝接受治疗
You don't know how hard things are already for me.
你不明白我已经过得多苦了
I can't handle any more.
我坚持不住了
I can't.
我不行了
I'm here to apologize.
我是来道歉的
I could have handled the news with more...
得知这个消息时 我应该处理得更...
Aplomb?
镇静?
I have a son. That's great news.
我有个儿子 好消息啊
What else did she tell you to say?
她还告诉你要说什么?
You're not a lunatic, you're not a mistake.
你不是疯子 不是一个错误
I never liked your friend... My father.
我从来都不像你的朋友...我的父亲
Well, he could be a bit intense at times.
他这人有时是挺难搞的
But unlike you, I did respect him.
但与你不同 我尊重他
Do you respect your mother?
你尊重你的母亲吗?
Well, we do have that in common.
好吧 我们这点倒是一样
And we all love her.
我们都爱她
So we don't have much choice, do we?
没有太多选择 对吧?
Son, see you at dinner.
儿子 晚餐见
Will, it's me.
Will 是我
Let me guess.
我猜猜
The doctor who thinks I'm an ass wants you to convince me to live.
觉得我是个混球的医生要你来说服我活下去
Yes.
是的
It won't work.
没用的
I KNOW.
我知道
So I won't.
所以我不劝你
Wow. You're that angry?
哇 你那么生气?
I've made enough decisions for you.
我已经替你做了够多决定了
This is your life.
这是你的人生
Why'd you come back?
你为什么要回来?
Because I love you.
因为我爱你
And I want to be with you for as long as I can.
我想尽可能多些时间和你在一起
Melissa, I'm so scared.
Melissa 我好怕
Me too.
我也是
I'll always love you.
我一直爱你
Even if I was deaf?
如果我聋了呢?
Even if anything.
怎样都无所谓
Is it working?
起效了吗?
He's still very ill,
他还是病得很重
but if he keeps responding the way he has been,
但如果这种反应继续下去
he should be fine.
他应该会没事的
And his hearing? It's gone.
- 他的听力呢? - 没了
We don't know yet if it'll be permanent.
我们还不清楚是不是永久性的
Melissa? Is that you?
Melissa? 是你吗?
We've been squeezing his hand, once for yes, twice for no.
我们一直在捏他的手 一次代表是 两次代表不
Can I ask you something?
我能问你点事吗?
I completely understand if you squeeze no.
如果你捏的是"不" 我完全明白
Will you marry me?
你愿意嫁给我吗?
Don't leave me hanging, now. Yes.
- 别晾着我啊 - 我愿意
Yes! Of course, yes!
愿意! 当然愿意了!
I- I heard that. You said yes, right?
我...我听到了 你说愿意 是吗?
Yes! You said y-
- 是的! - 你说愿...
How long are you gonna wait until you tell me?
你要等多久 才肯告诉我?
I thought we already had the Santa Claus talk.
我以为咱们已经说过圣诞老人的事了
You don't think I saw you steal Thomas' fork from the restaurant?
以为我看不到你在餐馆偷走Thomas的叉子了吗?
Why would I do that? For his DNA.
- 我为什么要那么做? - 为了拿到他的DNA
That's... That's...
那是... 那是...
Very observant of you.
你观察力很好
See, you're more me than you pretend. You had to know for sure.
瞧 你本质上和我 还是很像的 这一点你要清楚
So you needed proof.
所以你需要证据
The fact that you haven't told me
但你并没有告诉我
can only mean...
只能意味着...
He isn't your father either.
他也不是你的父亲
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
You know what that means. Your mom's a slut.
- 你知道这是什么意思 - 你妈是个荡妇
That...
这是一点...
And... she's not as boring as I thought she was.
还有....
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入